# ADAM STEININGER

**♦:** 1500 Gifford Dr. Longmont, CO 80501 **2:** 720-487-6821 **2:** deadleaves 15@gmail.com

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Writer from a creative, energetic, and perceptive environment. Passionate about exploring, researching, reporting and communicating news and researched information in the best possible way by utilizing acquired journalism/content writing skills. Highly organized, independent, and efficient in fast-paced multitasking environments; able to manage multiple responsibilities and prioritize effectively to accomplish objectives.

#### **SKILLS HIGHLIGHTS**

- Active Listening
- Creative Writing
- Judgment and Decision Making
- Research

- Reading Comprehension
- Social Perceptiveness
- Communications and Media
- Editing and Proofreading
- Critical Thinking
- Time Management
- HTML/CSS
- Teamwork

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Content & Compliance Lead Coordinator, LFP Broadcasting 6000 Spine Road, Boulder, CO 80301, (303) 786-8700

10/20-Present

- -Responsible for maintaining effective relationship with clients while establishing excellent customer service.
- -Review several aspects of documents and releases, and accurately record information into computer programs.
- -Consistently keep sensitive customer and/or company information confidential.
- -Analyze data for errors and similarities and report any discrepancies in data system to reporting manager.
- -Use several analytical tools for assuring quality and completeness of data.
- -Work with other team members to complete special projects and achieve project deadlines.
- -Adhere to all necessary compliance requirements.
- -Perform required filing according to requirement.
- -Audit data and information.
- -Manage incoming communication regarding changes in information and data.
- -Adhere to all compliance policies and procedures, implementing necessary new regulations and statutes.

# SENIOR REPORTER Aug 2017-May 2020

#### Longmont Observer - Longmont, CO

- Arranged interviews with people who can provide information about a story.
- Reviewed and corrected errors in content, grammar, and punctuation, following prescribed editorial style
  and formatting guidelines.
- Reviewed and evaluated notes taken about event aspects in order to isolate pertinent facts and details.
- Determined a story's emphasis, length, and format, and organize material accordingly.
- Researched and analyzed background information related to stories by ensuring complete and accurate information.
- Gathered information about events through research, interviews, experience, or attendance at political, news, artistic, social, or other functions.
- Checked reference materials, such as books, news files, or public records, to obtain relevant facts.
- Discussed issues with editors to establish priorities or positions.
- Revised work to meet editorial approval on or ahead of schedule in deadline-focused environment.

#### Ibotta - Denver, CO

- Responsible for maintaining effective relationship with clients while establishing excellent customer service.
- Review several aspects of receipts and accurately record information into various computer programs.
- Consistently keep sensitive customer and/or company information confidential.
- Analyze data for errors and similarities and report any discrepancies in data system to reporting manager.
- Use several analytical tools for assuring quality and completeness of data.
- Work with other team members to complete special projects and achieve project deadlines.

CONTRIBUTOR May 2013-June 2015

#### Westword - Denver, CO

- Arranged interviews with people who can provide information about a story.
- Reviewed and corrected errors in content, grammar, and punctuation, following prescribed editorial style and formatting guidelines.
- Reviewed and evaluated notes taken about event aspects in order to isolate pertinent facts and details.
- Determined a story's emphasis, length, and format, and organize material accordingly.
- Researched and analyzed background information related to stories by ensuring complete and accurate information.
- Gathered information about events through research, interviews, experience, or attendance at political, news, artistic, social, or other functions.
- Checked reference materials, such as books, news files, or public records, to obtain relevant facts.
- Discussed issues with editors to establish priorities or positions.
- Revised work to meet editorial approval on or ahead of schedule in deadline-focused environment.

#### WEB CONTENT ASSISTANT

Aug 2014 - Jan 2015

### University of Colorado/Auraria Library Denver, CO

- Expertly wrote reviews of literary, musical, or other artwork, based on knowledge, judgment or experience.
- Checked reference materials, such as books, news files, or public records, to obtain relevant facts.
- Researched and compiled web content on specialized fields such as medicine, science and technology, politics, foreign affairs, sports, arts, consumer affairs, business, religion, crime, or education.
- Wrote for use by publication, broadcast or internet media to promote the use of goods and services.
- Varied language and tone of messages based on product and medium.
- Organized material and completed writing assignment according to set standards regarding order, clarity, conciseness, style, and terminology.

#### **STAFF WRITER/EDITOR**

Oct 2011 -Jun 2014

# University of Colorado/The Advocate - Denver, CO

- Reported stories for publication, describing the background and details of events.
- Researched information using enhanced analytical abilities.
- Reviewed copy and corrected errors in content, grammar, and punctuation, following prescribed editorial style
  and formatting guidelines.
- Determined a story's emphasis, length, and format, and organize material accordingly.
- Consistently met rigorous deadlines despite unforeseeable adversities.
- Developed ideas or material for columns or commentaries by analyzing and interpreting news, current issues, or personal experiences.
- Planned the contents of publications according to the publication's style, editorial policy, and publishing requirements.
- Read, evaluated and edited articles or other materials submitted for publication and confer with authors regarding changes in content, style or organization, or publication.
- Assigned topics, events and stories to individual writers or reporters for coverage.
- Conferred with management and editorial staff members regarding placement and emphasis of developing news stories.

- Prepared, rewrote and edited copy to improve readability
- Supervised and coordinated work of reporters and other editors.
- Discussed issues with editors to establish priorities or positions.
- Wrote reviews of literary, musical, or other artwork, based on knowledge, judgment, or experience.

# **EDUCATION**

 $\ \, \textbf{University of Colorado Denver - Denver CO} \\$ 

Bachelor of Arts in English Writing